<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tool on Living and Programming - YJ Park&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/tool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tool on Living and Programming - YJ Park&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SILP: Simple Individual Line Preprocessor</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/04/12/silp-simple-individual-line-preprocessor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>/blog/2014/04/12/silp-simple-individual-line-preprocessor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-bother-with-a-preprocessor&#34;&gt;Why bother with a preprocessor?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was quite busy working on our &lt;a href=&#34;http://emberconflict.com/&#34;&gt;RTS game on iPad&lt;/a&gt; for almost a year, we are quite close to our first public version now. It&amp;rsquo;s developed with Unity3d, using uLink as the network library. Created a quite nice data context system on Unity3d, so non-developers can update pure visual part of the system without developers&amp;rsquo; help, will write some entries on it later when got time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SILP is a very small side project come from the process working on it. It&amp;rsquo;s a simple language-agnostic preprocessor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many discussions about whether a programming language should include preprocessor, most people seems agree that preprocessor is too error-prune and sacrifice readability too badly, and there should be seldom cases that an alternative can&amp;rsquo;t be find to replace the preprocessor usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree that in most cases we don&amp;rsquo;t need preprocessor though there are several cases that I would like to have a preprocessor in my tool set for cleaner codes or can remove some trivial typing. Here are 2 examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Day One Summary to Evernote</title>
      <link>/blog/2014/01/21/save-day-one-summary-to-evernote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>/blog/2014/01/21/save-day-one-summary-to-evernote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-not-just-use-evernote&#34;&gt;Why Not Just Use Evernote?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Evernote for several years, which is great, the best features to me are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi devices synchronization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High quality app on iOS/Android and OSX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good search in notes (even in the photos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though lately I found myself write less an less in Evernote, if I&amp;rsquo;m writing something long, then usually I will use MacVim, may copy the text back to Evernote. If I need to write a couple of line, the process to write in Evernote is like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch to Evernote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find the note for current day (each day I will have a new note.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the end of the note&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feels a bit heavy, also there is no information about when I did add the line into the note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantUML Plugin for Octopress</title>
      <link>/blog/2012/04/30/plantuml-plugin-for-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>/blog/2012/04/30/plantuml-plugin-for-octopress/</guid>
      <description>What is PlantUML? PlantUML is a component that allows to quickly write:
 sequence diagram, use case diagram, class diagram, activity diagram, component diagram, state diagram object diagram  I really like the idea of writing UML diagram with plain text. Since it&amp;rsquo;s totally plaintext, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to do diff and version track, also you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything about the layout (the text itself looks pretty good too).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>