<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game on Living and Programming - YJ Park&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.yjpark.org/categories/game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game on Living and Programming - YJ Park&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</webMaster>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.yjpark.org/categories/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>F# Game Tutorial Preface</title>
      <link>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2019/01/06/fsharp-game-tutorial-preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2019/01/06/fsharp-game-tutorial-preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before start writing individual posts, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about some general ideas about this tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience-who&#34;&gt;Target Audience (Who)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiar with at least one programming language, and don&amp;rsquo;t mind to try a new one (if you don&amp;rsquo;t know F# before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interested in game development, want to create some simple games for fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have some time to spare, to really learn something like writing a game from scratch, plan to spend a lot time on it, it&amp;rsquo;s really fun to me, but also quite hard at first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;planned-contents-what&#34;&gt;Planned Contents (What)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will write serious of posts about how to create this tank game from scratch, talking about what tasks need to be done, how to get each step forward, readers with no experiences should be able to follow these posts, and hopefully learn enough to create their own game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Along the way, I may also write some posts on specific topics, which may not directly related to current steps, but related to game development in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F# Game Tutorial Overview</title>
      <link>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2019/01/02/fsharp-game-tutorial-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2019/01/02/fsharp-game-tutorial-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have been working on game development for a few years now, making game is indeed quite fun, it shares much with other kind of software development, while it also has its uniqueness. Always wanted to write more on it, though not really have good idea about how to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a couple of game engines, mostly Unity3D, IwGame on Marmalade, Cocos2D, Phaser, created some own frameworks, did experiment with a very simple game engine in Elm as well. Most of them were designed in a similar way, provide similar components and tools. As game developers, we usually don&amp;rsquo;t need to dig much in the game engine itself, but we should have a rather clear understanding about its structure so we can work on it efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write some tutorials on game development, a very basic one, in my mind, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly for developers without much experiences with game development, but curious in it. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share some of my understandings with game development, explain core components of game engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.yjpark.org/img/game_tutorial/intro.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Engine Based on Marmalade and IwGame</title>
      <link>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2012/08/30/game-engine-based-on-marmalade-and-iwgame/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>yjpark@gmail.com (YJ Park)</author>
      <guid>http://blog.yjpark.org/blog/2012/08/30/game-engine-based-on-marmalade-and-iwgame/</guid>
      <description>Since August 2012, 2 developers(including me) and 2 graphic designers come together and started a small game studio to work on some mobile casual games, as the tech lead, I need to choose a development way for our first batch of games.
Our games will be mostly 2D games, might with some 3D charactors, though the scenes or levels will be 2D, I think that&amp;rsquo;s better for the team and the graphic quality of the games.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>